Microsoft's accessibility checker will
automatically test to see if you have
any color contrast issues in your
document. On the screen here, I have a
table with a title and the title is in
black text on a dark red background.
Next below that there is the table
itself that has a row header that is
dark gray and the text in each of the
items is black. So you have black text
on a dark gray background which is some
issues with color contrast. So at the
bottom status bar you have an
accessibility investigate button that
you can click on or you can go through
the menu uh and ribbons to investigate
the accessibility which will pop up the
accessibility assistant. You can do
quick fix which uh is one way to resolve
the issues or you can go through each
one. And here I'm going to go to the
color and contrast hard to read contrast
which says that there are six issues.
I'm going to click on that and it's
showing me issue number one which is the
title of the table which is that black
text on a maroon background. And it's
suggesting to change the black text to
either gray or a blue color. I'll try
blue. There we go. And now it's going
through and uh going to go through each
one of the column headers and suggest
what uh changing those colors. And you
can either use your own or you can try
one of the defaults here. So we're going
to pick the uh a lighter gray instead of
the um black. And so we'll go through
here. Now Q2 is looking good. We have
two more color contrast issues to
resolve. We'll use the again the lighter
gray for Q3. And for the final column
Q4, we're going to also select that. And
now our table is uh the color contrast
is now not an issue. And the
accessibility uh assistant says looks
good. No more issues.